Commons, John R. Collection on Microfilm 5738 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
John R. Commons Collection on Microfilm
1859-1967
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Commons, John R.
5738 mf
2.67 cubic feet
24 microfilm reels
Records (documents), microfilm.
"The Commons papers date 1859-1967, although the vast majority fall within the years 1887-1945" from the Scope and Content Note of the Guide.
5699099
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 12, 2019
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 12, 2019
Biographical / Historical
John R. Commons was born in Hollansburg, Ohio, October 13, 1862, he died May 11, 1945.
After graduating from Oberlin College, Commons earned his PhD at Johns Hopkins University. After appointments at Oberlin and Indiana University, he began teaching at Syracuse University. He was dismissed from Syracuse in 1899, after being considered a radical.
Commons' early work exemplified his desire to unite Christian ideals with the emerging social sciences of sociology and economics.
Common's contribution to labor history is considered equal to his contibutions to the theory of institutional economics.
Scope and Contents
Reels 1-5 -- General correspondence, 1859, 1894-1967
Reels 6-8 -- Unemployment insurance for the Chicago Clothing Market, 1922-1929
Reels 9-11 -- Research files, 1875-1932
Reels 12-14 -- Book Manuscripts
Reels 15-17 -- Articles, speeches, and miscellaneous writings, chronological file, scrapbooks, 1887-1918, 1938-1943
Reels 17-18 -- Unbound, 1908-1933
Reels 19-21 -- Topical file, 1892-1938. Reels 21-22 -- Newspaper clippings, 1906-1936
Reels 22-24 -- University file, 1910-1967
Reels 24 -- Photographs, 1881-1934
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4057: James A. Gross NLRB Files /4073: James O. Morris Office Files 5001 mf: American Association for Labor Legislation Records on Microfilm 5001 PAM: American Association for Labor Legislation Pamphlet File 5236: Edwin Emil Witte Papers 5618: Charles D. Wrege Research Papers Regarding History of Management 5780/047: ILGWU Joint Board Dress & Waistmakers' Union of Greater New York Managers' Correspondence 5912m: John R. Commons "Accident Prevention, Health and Group Insurance" Manuscript 6014: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Documents 6034: Rare Pamphlet Collection 6206: Clyde Summers Office Files
Unemployment insurance.; Commons, John R. (John Rogers),, 1862-1945.; Miller, Harold L., 1949-
5699099
- Index to General Correspondence and General Correspondence -- 1859-1911 (Reel 1)
- General Correspondence -- 1911-1915 (Reel 2)
- General Correspondence -- 1916-1924 (Reel 3)
- General Correspondence -- 1924-1930 (Reel 4)
- General Correspondence -- 1930-1967 (Reel 5)
- Unemployment Insurance for the Chicago Clothing Market - Accounts -- Accounts (Reel 6)
- Unemployment Insurance for the Chicago Clothing Market - Accounts -- Laws (Reel 7)
- Unemployment Insurance for the Chicago Clothing Market - Rules -- Trade (Reel 8)
- Research Files - American - Federal (Reel 9)
- Research Files - Government - Public (Reel 10)
- Research Files - Research - Wisconsin (Reel 11)
- Manuscript Copies of Books and Articles (Reel 12)
- Manuscript Copies of Books and Articles (Reel 13)
- Manuscript Copies of Books and Articles and Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings (Reel 14)
- Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings -- 1887-1902 (Reel 15)
- Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings -- 1902-1910 (Reel 16)
- Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings -- 1906-1922 (Reel 17)
- Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings -- 1923-1933 (Reel 18)
- Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings -- 1892-1927 (Reel 19)
- Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings -- 1895-1929 (Reel 20)
- Articles, Speeches and Miscellaneous Writings -- 1921-1938 and Newspaper Clippings (Reel 21)
- Newspaper Clippings and University Files Advisors - Friday (Reel 22)
- University Files - Grades - University and Photographs (Reel 23)
- Photographs (Reel 24)